A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 11775-13948 FA739E
Rockefeller Archive Center
- A review of the Ford Foundation's cultural grantmaking in Asia, 1994 Jan. (Reports 012594) (Box 630)
  Arts -- Finance -- Asia; Theater -- India; Mural painting and decoration -- Conservation and restoration -- Thailand; Performing arts -- Indonesia; Archaeology -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Bangladesh; Ford Foundation Education and Culture Program development Asia
- Evaluation of the Quantum Opportunities Program (QUOP): did the program work?: a report on the post secondary outcomes and cost-effectiveness of the QUOP program (1989-1993), 1994 Jun. (Reports 012595) (Box 630)
  Evaluation of the Quantum Opportunities Project, a multi-level demonstration funded by the Ford Foundation in San Antonio, Milwaukee, Saginaw, Philadelphia, and Oklahoma City. Each program was run by a local affiliate of Opportunities Industrialization Ce
  08800622;880-0623.
  3 v., ca. 106 leaves and pages in various paginations and foliations.
  Poor teenagers -- Services for -- United States -- Evaluation; Socially handicapped youth -- Education, Secondary -- United States; Action research -- United States; Social case work with youth -- United States -- Evaluation; Minority students -- Services for; Opportunities Industrialization Centers of America OIC Evaluation; Quantum Opportunities Program QUOP
- Review meeting: Bangkok (Reports 012596), 1992 (Box 630)
  Reports on a meeting held at the Ford Foundation's Bangkok office to plan a review of the Foundation's culture programs in Asia. Memorandum to Peter Geithner, Director, Asia Programs and the Culture Review Working Group.
  Arts -- Finance -- Asia; Performing arts -- Asia; Ford Foundation. Education and Culture Program development Asia
- A Review of public education and constituency building programs for Africa, for the Ford Foundation and the Carnegie Corporation, December 10 (Reports 012597), 1993 (Box 630)
  Philanthropy -- Africa; Endowments -- Africa; Education, Higher -- Africa
- The Ford Foundation campus diversity communications project meeting (Reports 012598), 1994 (Box 630)
  Contains 9 pages of rapporteur notes of a meeting between Foundation staff and an advisory group of communications consultants at Georgetown University gathered to discuss the launching of the Foundation's Campus Diversity Communications Project in 1995.
  09300967
  Multicultural education -- United States -- Public opinion; Education, Higher -- United States -- Curricula; Ford Foundation. Race Relations/Campus Diversity Initiative
- Consultant report: European Cooperation Fund (Reports 012599), 1994 (Box 630)
  Reviews project workshop, titled "Reconciliation Procedures in Parliament" held in cooperation with the Inter-Parliamentary Assembly of the Commonwealth of Independent States and the Committee on International Affairs of the Council of the Federation of t
  Rights and Social Justice;International Affairs
  09001360
  European Cooperation Fund
  Representative government and representation; Parliamentary practice; Russia (Federation). Federalʹnoe Sobranie
- Ford Foundation, Population program conference, Marino, Italy, 1970: Transcript of conference proceedings 6 volumes (Reports 012600) (Box 630-631)
  Transcripts (typescript carbon copy) of 18 audiotapes of sessions of a Ford Foundation conference to evaluate the Foundation's population/family planning program.
  07090157
  1 archives box (2.5 linear inches).
  Ford Foundation, Population program conference, Marino, Italy, 1970
  Population research; Population assistance; Birth control; Family policy; Ford Foundation
- General principles regarding establishment of foundations and their legal status, 1994/ Ewa Skupinska. (Reports 012601) (Box 631)
  Report prepared as part of the Foundation's explorations of the possibility of opening a field office in Warsaw. Discusses the particulars--especially the legal constraints--of establishing a foundation in Poland.
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Law and legislation -- Poland
- Re-thinking the Latin America and Caribbean regional program strategy (Reports 012602), 1994 (Box 631)
  23 leaves: graph -- 28 cm.
  Endowments -- Latin America -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Caribbean Area -- Evaluation; Ford Foundation
- Developing priorities for K-12 public policy and school reform, 1994 Dec. (Reports 012603) (Box 631)
  In addition to the 5-page report, contains a list of "Selected Current and Prospective Grants" and an article from Education Week [Oct. 12, 1994] by Don Davies entitled "Partnerships for Reform: Change Happens at the Local Level, and Must Link Family, Com
  Board of Trustees;Education and Culture
  Educational exchanges -- United States; School improvement programs -- United States; Ford Foundation Education and Culture Program development
- Education grantmaking in Latin America: new directions, 1994 Dec. (Reports 012604) (Box 631)
  In addition to the 5-page report, contains a list of Latin America grants for FY '94 and an Inter-American Dialogue policy brief (Aug. 1994) by Jeffrey M. Puryear and Jose Joaquin Brunner entitled "An Agenda for Educational Reform in Latin America and the
  Board of Trustees;Latin America and the Caribbean;Education and Culture
  Education -- Latin America; Ford Foundation Latin America and the Caribbean Program development; Ford Foundation Education and Culture Program development Latin America; Ford Foundation Grantmaking Latin America
- Development of work on Muslim societies in international affairs, 1994 Dec. (Reports 012605) (Box 631)
  Updates Trustees "about efforts to initiate programming on the evolution and roles of Muslim societies" by the International Affairs Program since the Foundation's June 1994 meeting, "Varieties of Muslim Experience."
  Islam -- 20th century; Muslims -- Public opinion; Ford Foundation. Varieties of Muslim Experience (1994 June 11-16: Istanbul, Turkey)
- An exploration of corporate involvement in community and economic development: staff working paper for discussion at the December 1994 meeting of the Special Committee on Program-Related Investments, 1994 Dec. (Reports 012606) (Box 631)
  Endowments -- United States -- Program-related investments; Social action -- United States; Community development -- United States; Corporations -- Charitable contributions -- United States; Corporations and community -- United States; Corporations, American; Ford Foundation Program-Related Investments Program development
- Program-Related Investments review paper: for discussion at the December 1994 meeting of the PRI Special Committee of the trustees, 1994 Dec. (Reports 012607) (Box 631)
  The report contains a background and fiscal summary section, a section on the contribution of the PRI office--including a summary of recent PRI initiatives, a review of the social purpose investment field and a discussion of recoverable grants for the pre
  Endowments -- Program-related investments; Social action -- United States; Ford Foundation Progam-Related Investments Program development
- Foundation work in Japan (Reports 012608), 1991 (Box 631)
  Memorandum to Shepard Forman.
  Philanthropy -- Japan; Ford Foundation
- Joint programming fund in international area and cultural studies (Reports 012609), 1994 (Box 631)
  Memorandum to Shepard Forman and Joseph Schull. Surveys emphases and priorities of major area studies centers that focus on the former Soviet Union and Eastern Europe.
  Foreign study -- United States; Ford Foundation International Affairs Program development
- Exit memo (Reports 012610), 1994 (Box 631)
  Memorandum to Shepard Forman, dated December 14, 1994.
  4 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Exit memo
  Endowments -- Russia (Federation) -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Europe, Central -- Evaluation; Social sciences -- Research -- Russia (Federation); Social sciences -- Research -- Europe, Central; Economics -- Research -- Russia (Federation); Economics -- Research -- Europe, Central; Ford Foundation. International Affairs
- The food economy in Eastern Europe: production reforms, international trade: papers presented during the Ninth International Conference on USSR and East European Agriculture, Ciechocinek, Poland, September 11-14, 1990. (Reports 012611) (Box 631)
  International Affairs;Rural Poverty and Resources
  09051234
  20 items.
  International Conference on USSR and East European Agriculture (9th: 1990: Ciechocinek, Poland)
  Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Europe, Eastern -- Congresses; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Soviet Union -- Congresses; Instytut Koniunktur i Cen Handlu Zagranicznego (Warsaw, Poland)
- The future and the welfare state: report prepared for the Ford Foundation, 1984 Aug. (Reports 012612) (Box 631)
  Study prepared as precursor to the Foundation publication, "The Common Good" (1989). Reviews current research on the welfare state and discusses role the Foundation might play. Contains bibliographical references.
  L83-310.
  Public welfare -- United States; Ford Foundation. Project on Social Welfare and the American Future
- Studies on the impact of the 1981 Omnibus Reconciliation Act on the working poor, 1982-1985. (Reports 012613)
  A coordinated set of studies and policy analyses on the working poor prepared by the Center for the Study of Social Policy. Includes reports of a three-state survey--Michigan, Georgia, New York--conducted by the University of Michigan, the University of G
  8200788
  The human face of poverty: beyond statistics;Restructuring unemployment insurance;On the edge: poverty, work and Reaganomics;Working female-headed families in poverty: three studies of low-income families affected by the AFDC policy changes of 1981;Eff
  Poor women -- Georgia -- Case studies; Poor women -- Michigan -- Case studies; Women heads of households -- Georgia -- Case studies; Women heads of households -- Michigan -- Case studies; Insurance, Unemployment -- United States; Federal aid to public welfare; Center for the Study of Social Policy (Washington, D.C.); University of Michigan. Center for Political Studies; University of Georgia; Columbia University; United States. Omnibus Reconciliation Act of 1981.; Aid to Families with Dependent Children AFDC
- The human face of poverty: Beyond statistics (Reports 012613-001), 1984 (Box 631)
  08200788
  [Studies on the impact of the 1981 Omnibus Reconciliation Act on the working poor], 1982-1985.
  Poor women -- Georgia -- Case studies; Poor women -- Michigan -- Case studies; Women heads of households -- Georgia -- Case studies; Women heads of households -- Michigan -- Case studies; Insurance, Unemployment -- United States; Federal aid to public welfare; Center for the Study of Social Policy (SRI International)
- Restructuring unemployment insurance (Reports 012613-002), 1985 (Box 631)
- On the edge: Poverty, work and Reganomics (Reports 012613-003), 1982 (Box 631)
- Effects of Federal AFDC policy changes: A study of a Federal-State "partnership" (Reports 012613-004), 1983 (Box 631)
- Working female-headed families in poverty: Three studies of low-income families affected by the AFDC policy changes of (Reports 012613-005), 1984 (Box 631)
- Summary of June 30, 1992 meeting on Central Asian Republics/Islamic societies (Reports 012614) (Box 631)
  Reports on meeting held to exchange information between field and New York-based program offices on programs dealing with Islamic societies, and on the Central Asian Republics of the former Soviet Union.
  Islam and world politics; Islam -- Social aspects; Ford Foundation Program development Asia, Central; Ford Foundation Program development Former Soviet republics; Ford Foundation Program development Islamic countries
- Arts stabilization: an emerging field, March, 1994 Volume 1 (Reports 012615-001) (Box 631-632)
  This report provides an overview of the field of arts stabilization. Volume 1 explains what is meant by term stabilization and outlines the characteristics of the field today. Volume 2 profiles representative arts stabilization programs around the United
  09300707
  Arts -- Finance -- United States -- Case studies; Arts -- Management -- United States -- Case studies; National Arts Stabilization Fund; National Arts Stabilization Fund; National Arts Stabilization; National Arts Strategies
- Arts stabilization: an emerging field, March, 1994 Volume 2 (Reports 012615-002)
- Varieties of Muslim experience: record of The Ford Foundation meeting, Istanbul, Turkey (Reports 012616), 1994 (Box 632)
  Contents: [1] Notes describing the meeting's background and summarizing its principal themes;[2] rapporteur notes covering presentations by outside scholars and exchanges that followed;[3] a summary of program-related discussions. Topics addressed include
  [1], 43 leaves.
  Islam and world politics; Islam and state; Islam -- 20th century; Muslim women -- Social conditions; Islamic fundamentalism; Muslims -- Social life and customs; Ford Foundation. Varieties of Muslim Experience (1994 June 11-16: Istanbul, Turkey); Ford Foundation Program development Islamic countries
- Memoranda from a trip to Israel, 1984 Apr. (Reports 012617) (Box 632)
  A series of informal memoranda to "The File" but sent to William Carmichael. Sick records what various people in Israel and the West Bank told him during a trip to Israel. Sick met with American, Israeli and Palestinian academics and politicians, includin
  10 items (31 leaves).
  Universities and colleges -- Israel; Research institutes -- Israel; Jewish-Arab relations -- 1973; Palestinian Arabs -- Government policy -- Israel
- Collection of political cartoons referring to the Ford Foundation, 195? (Reports 012618), 1981 (Box 632)
  Photocopies of political cartoons from various newspapers and magazines, ca. 1955-1981.
  [18] leaves: ill. -- 28 cm.
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Humor; Ford Foundation
- Governance and public policy: a programming strategy, 1992 Nov. (Reports 012619) (Box 632)
  "The report is primarily based on consultation held in Bangladesh with different groups of individuals during October 15-29, 1992. The list of persons consulted is annexed."-p.2.
  ii, 26 leaves.
  Public policy (Law) -- Bangladesh; Civil society -- Bangladesh; Non-governmental organizations -- Bangladesh; Ford Foundation Governance and Public Policy Program development Bangladesh
- Human rights and social justice grant-making across thematic areas in Asia: an overview, FY 1983 to FY 1992 1993?. (Reports 012620) (Box 632)
  Reviews the general contours of the rights and social justice programs of the Ford Foundation in the Philippines, Indonesia, India, Bangladesh and China and examines their intersections with other program areas, especially women's rights and rural poverty
  Human rights -- Asia; Ford Foundation. Rights and Social Justice Philippines; Ford Foundation. Rights and Social Justice Indonesia; Ford Foundation. Rights and Social Justice India; Ford Foundation. Rights and Social Justice Bangladesh; Ford Foundation. Rights and Social Justice C
- Overseas Development review notebook (Reports 012621), 1955 (Box 632)
  Notebook assembled by Nielsen in the course of his review.
  Office of the President;Overseas Division
  1 v.: var. pag.: tables
  Technical assistance -- Developing countries; Endowments -- Developing countries -- Evaluation; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Administration; Ford Foundation. Overseas Development
- Review of US-based institutions funded by the Ford Foundation engaged in policy related research on immigration and refugee matters (Reports 012622), 1991 (Box 632)
  Reviews the immigration and refugee policy research programs of the Refugee Policy Group, the Program for Research on Immigration Policy of the Rand Corporation and the Urban Institute, and the Immigration Policy Project of the Carnegie Endowment for Inte
  International Affairs;Governance and Public Policy;Rights and Social Justice
  v.(ca. 160 pages and leaves in various paginations).
  Review of U.S.-based institutions funded by the Ford Foundation engaged in policy related research on immigration and refugee matters
  Refugees -- Government policy -- United States -- Research; Refugee Policy Group RPG Evaluation; Program for Research on Immigration Policy (U.S.) Evaluation; Immigration Policy Project (U.S.) Evaluation
- Expanding and strengthening the public policy role of black scholars: a preliminary report (Reports 012623), 1993 (Box 632)
  In addition to 12-page report, contains transcript of a meeting held by the authors with other experts in the field at the University of Michigan on July 27, 1992;lists of potential informants and of those actually consulted;interview questions;and cover
  0L93-22.
  [1], [2], 12, [2], 35, [6] leaves.
  Transcript of the Ford Foundation meeting on blacks in public policy
  Policy sciences -- Research -- United States; Policy scientists -- United States -- Education; Minorities in policy sciences -- United States; African Americans -- Education; Afro-American scholars; Ford Foundation Governance and Public Policy Program development
- New York office reports: December 1952 (Reports 012624) (Box 632)
  Memoranda written by Gladieux to the president and offices of the Ford Foundation in Pasadena and Detroit, every one to three weeks, detailing the activities of the New York Office.
  10 v.: var. pag. -- 28 cm.
- Risky business: an overview of the crisis in liability insurance 1985 Sept.? (Reports 012625) (Box 632)
  "Background paper by Alan Guttmacher Institute staff for a September meeting on product liability and medical malpractice insurance as it affects contraceptive development, manufacture and distribution." - cover memorandum by Oscar Harkavy to members of t
  United States and International Affairs Program/Urban Poverty program;United States and International Affairs Program/Office of the Vice President
  L85-209.
  [1], 46 leaves.
  Liability (Law) -- United States; Insurance, Products liability; Insurance, Malpractice; Contraceptives; Alan Guttmacher Institute; Ford Foundation. Liability Insurance Working Group
- IRIS computer file: an interactive river system simulation program (Reports 012626), 1989 (Box 632)
  Simulation program/decision support system to estimate physical impacts of alternative water resource system design, management, and operating policies over time and space. Funded by the Ford Foundation through a grant to the American Academy of Arts and
  United States and International Affairs Program/International Affairs;United States and International Affairs Program/Rural Poverty and Resources
  08501034
  2 computer diskettes, 5.25 in., 3.5 in. + 2v. (73p., 105p.).
  IRIS: interactive river system simulation program: general introduction and simulation;IRIS: interactive river system simulation program: user's manual
  River engineering -- Computer simulation; Water use -- Computer simulation; Decision support systems; International Institute for Applied Systems Analysis; Cornell University. School of Civil and Environmental Engineering
- Program directions in the Middle East by geography (Reports 012627), 1972 (Box 632, Reel R-9303)
  A memorandum to David E. Bell, VP, International Division, describing past, present and future programming in the Middle East country by country.
  Technical assistance -- Middle East; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa History; Ford Foundation Middle East; Ford Foundation Middle East and Africa Program development
- A study or paternity decisions of young, unmarried parents: final report submitted to the Ford Foundation (Reports 012628), 1991 (Box 633)
  In addition to 106-page report, contains addenda with profiles of respondents and 4 appendices detailing Minnesota paternity statutes, legal benefits to the child when paternity is established, questionnaire responses and questionnaire.
  08800964
  106, [40] leaves.
  Study of paternity decisions: perspectives from young mothers and young fathers
  Paternity -- United States -- Decision making; Unmarried fathers -- Legal status, laws, etc.; Unmarried mothers -- United States; Parent and child (Law) -- United States; University of Minnesota. Center for Urban and Regional Affairs
- Work with the South African Legal Resources Centre January to July, 1979 (Reports 012629) (Box 633)
  Purpose of trip was to consult with the new Legal Resources Centre (LRC) and to assist it in developing a law clinic program in Johannesburg in conjunction with the University of the Witwatersrand, and secondarily, to investigate possibility of developing
  07890705
  54 leaves + offprint.
  Public interest law: South African style
  Law -- Study and teaching (Clinical education) -- South Africa; Law schools -- South Africa; Legal services -- South Africa; Public interest law -- South Africa; Legal aid -- South Africa; Legal assistance to the poor -- South Africa; Blacks -- Legal status, laws, etc.; Legal Resources Centre (Durban, South Africa); University of the Witwatersrand. Faculty of Law
- Urban economic development programs: a case study analysis, 1990 Oct. (Reports 012630) (Box 633)
  Report presents case studies in 3 cities - Baltimore, Dayton and Long Beach. Includes examples of economic development programs that address labor supply as well as those intended to stimulate labor demand.
  08900915
  Economic development projects -- Maryland -- Baltimore (Md.) -- Case studies; Economic development projects -- Ohio -- Dayton -- Case studies; Community development, Urban -- Maryland -- Baltimore (Md.) -- Case studies; Community development, Urban -- Ohio -- Dayton; NCI Research (Organization)
- Report on the status of women in the Czech and Slovak Federal Republic, Hungary, and Poland, 1992 Fall (Reports 012631) (Box 633)
  Contains introductory overview and three chapters reviewing the status of women in the Czech lands and Slovakia, Poland and Hungary. Each chapter provides a historical overview of the status of women, and discusses their current socio-economic and legal s
  ca. 160 leaves in various foliations.
  Women -- Legal status, laws, etc.; Women -- Legal status, laws, etc.; Women -- Legal status, laws, etc.; Women -- Poland -- Social conditions; Women -- Hungary -- Social conditions; Women -- Czechoslovakia -- Social condi
- The Ford Foundation's international human rights program (Reports 012632), 1995 (Box 633)
  "The paper traces the evolution of Foundation programs to advance adherence to human rights in different societies and cultures around the world. It provides a general overview of the support the Foundation has provided worldwide, it does not provide a de
  Human rights; Social justice; Human rights advocacy; Developing countries -- Social conditions; Human rights -- Developing countries; Ford Foundation. International Affairs; Ford Foundation Program Development -- Human rights
- Promoting rights and social justice: A historical survey of Ford Foundation programs for African American and Latino communities, 1994 Nov. (Reports 012633) (Box 633)
  African Americans -- Civil rights; Hispanic Americans -- Civil rights; Minorities -- Civil rights; Minorities -- Legal status, laws, etc.; Ford Foundation. Rights and Social Justice History; Ford Foundation Rights and Social Justice Program development
- Transfer education in Southwest border community colleges: final report of the Ford Southwest Transfer Education Project: submitted to Alison Bernstein, the Ford Foundation (Reports 012634), 1988 (Box 633)
  This study of the causative factors for low rates of transfer from community colleges to baccalaureate degree-granting institutions focused on the six member community colleges of the Border College Consortium: Arizona Western College, Cochise College, Im
  08601101
  171, 6, [62], 21 leaves, 14, 10 p., 30 leaves.